So this is going to be very valuable for you
to learn a lot and I'm just going to go
over my favorite method,
which ties everything together, which will summarize what I'm talking
about in this episode.
But most of them to give you some examples from
my life as well,
which will help you understand just the importance of this
concept
of embracing when things get difficult now to embrace something
means to learn to live it,
to see as a. Positive thing instead of a negative
thing.
But before we get into that,
let's just talk about deliberate learning versus passive learning.
I'll give you an example.
So deliberate learning is something like learning grammar rules.
So let's say you are in a language school
and your teacher says, OK,
let's learn the present perfect.
This is when
we use it. These are the rules,
and you have to focus on that and try to
memorize it.
Try to learn these concepts.
Passive learning is when you are watching a TV program
in English and you are just naturally getting that input
which I've talked about a lot is so important to
get input because that's how you're going to really absorb
English and just getting used to the English language.
But we have to set up that again,
is deliberate learning grammar rules when you focus on learning
new words and phrases when you use a method that
I'm going to talk about later.
When you try to learn how to say a word
that is difficult for you to say,
and you practice this a few times and you practice
it again next week,
that is deliberate learning now,
deliberate learning needs more focus,
it needs more focus because let's say you are watching
a YouTube video in English,
you can sometimes just switch off maybe.